ANDRE BOULAY: So, next, I want to show you how to actually throw an off string yoyo.
The traditional throw is actually from a forward pass which we touched on in both the string trick and looping sections.
So if you didn't learn to forward pass yet, go take a look at that section.
It is really important in order to do off string tricks.
So, you got your yoyo.
I want you to wind it up and what you're going to do is you're going to hold it as if you're doing a forward pass.
I learned how to do it outside.
I highly recommend doing that, because it can definitely fly off.
Even you're good at it and every now and then you get a bad throw, and it might shoot up into the air.
So, it's just like that.
You throw, release, it lands onto the string.
The second part is called the bind.
If you haven't learn how to bind, I definitely recommend going to the single A section, but basically what you're doing is you're taking the string up here in my non-throw hand pointer here.
And I'm taking it and point it down over the yoyo.
It's actually going to grab the yoyo and return it back.
Let me just grab my yoyo here.
I'll show you really quick what that looks like.
So if the yoyo was on the string spinning, I would pull the string down over it, almost as if you're actually going to wind it.
And what happens is, because it's spinning, it's going to shoot that yoyo right back up to your hand.
The reason I didn't grab before was I didn't pull quite fast enough cause I was trying to show you guys what it looks like.